export const data = [
  {
    question: "What is the purpose of HTML forms?",
    option1: "To define the structure of a webpage.",
    option2: "To create interactive elements for user input.",
    option3: "To style HTML elements.",
    option4: "To add multimedia content to a webpage.",
    ans: 2,
  },
  {
    question: "What does the 'action' attribute in a form specify?",
    option1: "The type of form element to be created.",
    option2: "The URL of the page to display when the form is submitted.",
    option3: "The default value of the text input element.",
    option4: "The URL of the image to be displayed.",
    ans: 4,
  },
  {
    question: "What is the purpose of the 'input' element in HTML?",
    option1: "To create a clickable button.",
    option2: "To create a dropdown list.",
    option3: "To create a form control that users can interact with.",
    option4: "To create a container for other HTML elements.",
    ans: 3,
  },
  {
    question: "What does the 'type' attribute in an input element specify?",
    option1: "The URL where the form data should be submitted.",
    option2: "The type of input element to display.",
    option3: "The name of the input element.",
    option4: "The default value of the input element.",
    ans: 2,
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the purpose of the 'value' attribute in an input element?",
    option1: "To specify the URL where the form data should be submitted.",
    option2: "To specify the default value of the input element.",
    option3: "To specify the type of input element to display.",
    option4: "To specify the name of the input element.",
    ans: 2,
  },
  {
    question:
      "What does the 'placeholder' attribute do in HTML form input elements?",
    option1:
      "It specifies a brief hint that describes the expected value of the input field.",
    option2: "It specifies the default value of the input field.",
    option3: "It specifies the maximum length of the input field.",
    option4: "It specifies that the input field is required.",
    ans: 1,
  },
  {
    question: "Which HTML element is used to create a drop-down list?",
    option1: "<input type='select'>",
    option2: "<dropdown>",
    option3: "<list>",
    option4: "<select>",
    ans: 4,
  },
  {
    question: "Which attribute is used to specify the name of the form?",
    option1: "name",
    option2: "id",
    option3: "form",
    option4: "action",
    ans: 1,
  },
  {
    question: "Which input type is used for a date picker?",
    option1: "datetime",
    option2: "date",
    option3: "calendar",
    option4: "datepicker",
    ans: 2,
  },
  {
    question: "Which HTML element is used to group related elements in a form?",
    option1: "<group>",
    option2: "<fieldset>",
    option3: "<grouping>",
    option4: "<section>",
    ans: 2,
  },
  {
    question:
      "What does the 'required' attribute do in HTML form input elements?",
    option1: "It specifies that the input field cannot be changed.",
    option2:
      "It specifies that the input field must be filled out before submitting the form.",
    option3: "It specifies the maximum length of the input field.",
    option4: "It specifies the default value of the input field.",
    ans: 2,
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the purpose of the 'autocomplete' attribute in HTML form input elements?",
    option1: "To provide suggestions as the user types.",
    option2: "To validate the input data.",
    option3: "To specify the default value of the input field.",
    option4: "To disable autocomplete for the input field.",
    ans: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which attribute is used to specify the URL where the form data will be submitted?",
    option1: "url",
    option2: "method",
    option3: "action",
    option4: "submit",
    ans: 3,
  },
  {
    question: "What is the purpose of the 'enctype' attribute in HTML forms?",
    option1:
      "It specifies the character encoding used when submitting the form.",
    option2: "It sets the maximum length of characters allowed in the form.",
    option3: "It defines the method used to submit the form.",
    option4: "It specifies the URL where the form data should be sent.",
    ans: 1,
  },
  {
    question: "What does the 'pattern' attribute do in an HTML form element?",
    option1:
      "It specifies a regular expression that the input element's value is checked against.",
    option2: "It specifies that the form element should be disabled.",
    option3:
      "It specifies the visible width, in characters, of an input element.",
    option4: "It specifies that the form element should be hidden.",
    ans: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the purpose of the 'min' and 'max' attributes in HTML form input elements?",
    option1:
      "To specify the minimum and maximum number of characters allowed in the input field.",
    option2:
      "To specify the minimum and maximum values allowed in the input field.",
    option3: "To specify the minimum and maximum width of the input field.",
    option4: "To specify the minimum and maximum height of the input field.",
    ans: 2,
  },
  {
    question: "Which input type is used for a file upload?",
    option1: "upload",
    option2: "action",
    option3: "text",
    option4: "file",
    ans: 4,
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the purpose of the 'readonly' attribute in HTML form input elements?",
    option1: "To specify that the input field cannot be changed.",
    option2: "To specify that the input field is required.",
    option3: "To specify the default value of the input field.",
    option4: "To specify the maximum length of the input field.",
    ans: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which attribute is used to associate a label with an input element?",
    option1: "label",
    option2: "for",
    option3: "id",
    option4: "name",
    ans: 2,
  },
  {
    question: "Which input type is used for a range slider?",
    option1: "slider",
    option2: "slide",
    option3: "scrollbar",
    option4: "range",
    ans: 4,
  },
];
